

Farouq Ayofe

Nationality: Nigerian (Nigeria)

(+353) 899832249

Date of birth: 12/02/1996

Gender: Male

Website: https://faroug.dev/

Skype: ayofef

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ayofef/

Address: 1, Tuscany Downs Raheny Co. Dublin, D05 YA36 Dublin (Ireland)

ABOUT ME

I'm a Front-end developer. Nigerian, currently living in Dublin, Ireland. After my college degree in "Mass Communication" which explored Broadcasting communications, Public relation and Advertising, I decided to change career path to client-side programming due to my aptitude in digital technology. I started my masters programme in "Applied Digital Media" in February 2018, at Griffith College Dublin, straight into the challenging world of Javascript using p5*. At the completion of my masters programme, I was conversant with Web development and Publishing, Game design, Visual Communication, Interaction Design and Data Visualization but my interest in Web development and User experience design made me took the career path as a Front-end Developer. Now, I design and develop experiences that makes people's live simple. I'm hard working, super curious, passionate, dedicated, and also a fast learner!

WORK EXPERIENCE

Part-time Sales assistant

Aim cash & carry [08/11/2018 - Current]

Address: Dublin (Ireland)

City: Dublin
Country: Ireland

o Stock management.

• Liaising with customers and helping them choose between the company's array of goods, process payments and maintain a high level of customer service.

Part-time Web Developer

Solid-Link Consulting [17/05/2019 - Current]

City: Dublin
Country: Ireland

- Website maintenance
- o Troubleshooting content issues.
- Monitoring the performance of the live website.

Graphic designer

Exotic Designs [05/05/2015 – 29/09/2015]

City: Ibadan Country: Nigeria

- Graphics Design
 Graphics Design
- General Printing

Web content manager - Internship

Nigerian Television Authority [01/05/2016 – 29/09/2016]

City: Ibadan Country: Nigeria

- Video Editing
- Assign Projects to departments
- o Managing the employees who works with the website's content.
- Uploading Approved content to the website

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

MSc. Applied Digital Media

Griffith College Dublin [16/02/2018 – 30/06/2019]

Address: Dublin (Ireland)
Level in EQF: EQF level 7

Web Development (Html, CSS, JavaScript)

Interaction Design (UI & UX)

Game Development (Unity 3d)

3D Modelling (Autodesk Max)

Multimedia Programming (JavaScript - p5*)

Visual Communication (Photoshop)

BSc. Mass Communication

Babcock University [01/09/2013 - 02/06/2017]

Address: Ogun State (Nigeria)
Level in EQF: EQF level 6

Public Relation

Advertising

Marketing

Brand Management

Consumer Behavior

Graphics Communication

Web Development (Adobe Dreamweaver)

Photo - Journalism

International Communication

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s):

Yoruba

English

LISTENING: C2 READING: C2 UNDERSTANDING: C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION: C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION: C2

RECOMMENDATIONS

-Ruairi Murphy
Lecturer,
Computer Science Department,
Griffith College.
01-4163340
ruairi.murphy@griffith.ie

-Olaniyi Kolawole CEO, Solid-Link Educational Consulting, Cork, Ireland. 0899864414

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Organisational skills

Super curious, passionate, dedicated, and also a fast learner. I'm confident I will thrive in any web development role and make positive contribution to your organization!

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Communication and interpersonal skills

Good communication skills earned on my previous jobs, where i talked directly with clients and customers and had to express my point of view or suggest a solution.

JOB-RELATED SKILLS

Job-related skills

HTML5 - CSS3 - JAVASCRIPT - Webpack - Babel - SASS - PHP - WordPress - Git - Adobe Photoshop - Adobe Xd - Bootstrap - ReactJS - GatsbyJS - CSS Modules - Styled Component - GraphQL - Headless CMS

CERTIFICATIONS

Certifications

New Horizons: Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Customer Relationship Management, Project Management

Udemy: Advanced CSS and Sass: Flexbox, Grid, Animations and More!

Udemy: The Complete JavaScript Course 2019: Build Real Projects!

Udemy: Complete WordPress Development Themes and Plugins Course.

Udemy: Git Complete: The definitive, step-by-step guide to Git.

Udemy: Bootstrap 4 From Scratch With 5 Projects.

Udemy: React - The Complete Guide.

Udemy: Typescript - The Complete Developer's Guide.